Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Photograph Collection, circa 1926-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Negatives for photographs in the collection circa 1926-1989, VIII.; Items 147-149
  - Color negatives for Leo Smit's photographs of Kachina dolls, circa 1980-1989, 13 negatives; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 2, Item smit149)
- Oversize color portrait of Leo Smit (3 copies), 1977, IX.; Items 150-152
  - Leo Smit color portrait, 1977, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item smit150)
  - Leo Smit color portrait, 1977, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item smit151)
  - Leo Smit color portrait, 1977, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item smit152)
- Additional photographs, circa 1950-1979, X.; Boxes 4-5 (306 items)
  Arranged in two subseries:
  A. People
  B. Places
  - People, circa 1950-1979, A.; Item 153-205
    Arranged in approximate topical order.
    - Leo Smit sitting in unidentified location, March 1959, 1 photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item smit153)
  - Places, circa 1950-1979, B.; Remainder of Box 4 and all Box 5 (154 items)
    Locations in the remainder of Box 4 include Italy and Turkey. Locations in Box 5 include sites in the Pacific Northwest, Canyon de Chelly in Arizona, Yosemite National Park, Mount McKinley, images from a television screen of a lunar landing, Rio de Janiero, and the Pyramid of the Magician in Uxmal, Mexico.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Musicians--Photographs; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999--Photographs
Genres
Photographs
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Leo Smit Score Collection, circa 1940-1998
Mus. Arc. 6.1
The collection consists of 104 scores by Leo Smit, principally in copies of holographs. There are also another 43 items arranged or transcribed by Smit, inscribed to or by Smit, scores marked for performance by Smit, and miscellaneous scores.
Leo Smit Papers, 1939-2000
Mus. Arc. 6.2
A small collection of personal documents, writings by Smit, correspondence (chiefly photocopies of letters from Aaron Copland to Smit), clippings, programs, and lecture materials.
Remembering Leo Smit (1921-1999)
An online exhibit commemorating the life and career of Leo Smit. It contains many images of Smit as well as photographs taken by him. A list of Smit's compositions, compiled by the composer, is also included.
Leo Smit Slide Collection, circa 1966-1991,
Mus. Arc. 6.3
A collection of Collection contains approximately 13,705 35 millimeter slides taken by Smit. The contents include images of notable musicians, images used in his lecture recitals, and images taken during his many journeys in the United States and abroad, including Central and South America, Italy, and various other European countries.
Related Resources Outside the Music Library
Guide to the Leo Smit Papers, 1905-1998
JPB 00-42
Finding aid for the collection at the New York Public Library for the Performing Arts. Music Division. The Leo Smit collection contains scores, correspondence, and research materials.